Now we're going to cover
the ITTOs of integration
management, Develop
Project Charter Process.
So I do recommend that you follow along in
your PIMBOC.
So we're on page 75, page 75.
All right, so develop project charter
process, if you look at page 75,
is we're creating a document to formally
get our project authorized.
rise to begin.
In the PMI world, we do not
have a project until we have a
project charter that is signed,
published by the sponsor.
All right, so it will show the business
justification for the project,
why the project exists.
So our inputs, information,
documentation, key to the
process, what are the
artifacts that will come in?
What do we need to review?
We'll have our business documents.
The business case does show.
show the feasibility, justification,
need of the project.
It goes hand in hand with
the benefits management
plan, how the project will
benefit the organization.
Project does help the organization meet
their strategic needs.
All right.
So what else comes in, agreements,
contracts.
So sales or business development landed a
project through the contract.
this process is where you will officially
be assigned all right then we have those
EEFs and OPAs so you can go to page 38 in
your PIMBOC enterprise environmental
factors are things beyond our control that
will impact us some of the main categories
organizational culture structure and
governance PMIS the project management
information system, which includes any
technology softwares we use, whether it's
Microsoft Project, Timberline,
Clarity, Primavera, SmartSheet,
or and Microsoft Office, Lotus Notes,
whatever you're using.
Then we have organizational resources,
people, material, equipment, supplies,
facilities, already with the organization.
Then on the next page, you'll see
government and industry standards,
laws, regulations, we're going to have to
follow.
So those are your main categories.
So anything external to the project,
anything that will impact us, marketplace
conditions, whether
we're at war, COVID, all
things beyond our
control that will impact us.
We have to be familiar with these and
consider these things.
So that's why they are inputs.
And you will see them throughout all the
integration and all our
planning processes.
over and over.
And if you see me do this, I'm going
through your process map.
I'm not doing Father, Son, Holy Ghost.
I'm going through your process map,
which is on page 25 of your Pimpock.
So we're in the integration knowledge
area.
All right.
What else comes in that we have to
consider our organizational process assets?
So I believe that's on page 41.
So these are the, or I think they start on
39, actually.
These are the policy.
these processes, procedures, guidelines,
methods we have to follow on our project.
The PMO is telling us these policies,
processes, procedures we have to follow.
The second part, which I believe is on
page 41, is the knowledge repository.
I want you to think anything you can pull
and use.
So big categories, configuration management,
the first one, that's version control.
To always make sure we're working from
the.
the latest versions, plans, baselines,
documents.
We'll also pull historical information and
lessons learned.
History is bound to repeat itself if we
don't know what it was.
I don't remember the exact saying,
but it's George Santiana.
So you document what's happened before.
The lessons learned, what's gone well,
what hasn't gone well.
So we can learn from these things too.
So these are things we'll pull and use.
The last one, your best friend, previous
similar recently completed project files.
Why would you reinvent the wheel?
If you have a previous similar
recently completed project
and you can look at the
plans, baselines, all right?
So tools and techniques, verbs,
what we will do in a process.
We'll use expert judgment.
We'll see this a lot.
We use ours, our team members, our
SMEs, subject matter experts, experiences.
and expertise to do this process.
We're using our brains.
We'll gather data.
We need some details.
So brainstorming small group tries to
generate as many ideas.
Here we're trying to generate as many high
level ideas as possible.
What needs to be in our project charter?
All high level details.
Focus groups.
You can do pre-qualified SMEs.
Ask them.
So these are usually people.
have some experience with these types of
projects and then we're going to interview
our sponsor key stakeholders what are your
high level needs we'll use interpersonal
team skills so anytime you see
interpersonal and team skills these are
our soft skills we're dealing with
stakeholders so some of the things we'll
do manage conflict will facilitate the
meetings come to some conclusion as we're
managing the meetings while we're having
meetings so a lot of these tools and
techniques are done concurrently so keep
that in mind your output another noun
inputs and outputs are artifacts outputs
are artifacts we create some form of
deliverable so the process is develop
project charter what do we produce the
project charter and i believe
it's on page 80 in your pinback
that will tell you the key
components of your project charter.
Again, I want you to think
high level requirements,
summary budget, summary
milestone schedule.
So high level.
And at least you are in there.
This is where you are assigned as a
project manager given authority levels and
authority to use resources to accomplish
project objectives.
So you and that sponsor or initiator are
listed in that project charter,
their authority levels.
So the sponsor is the one funding your
project.
All right, what else do we create?
Any other high level details that we know
about, like overall project success
criteria, exit criteria,
measurable project objectives, any
key stakeholders we know
about, any risks we know about.
Your project charter will contain all your
high level details.
What else do we create when
we develop project charter
process will be our
assumptions and constraints log?
So I know it just says
assumptions log, but I
want you to think
assumptions and constraints.
So we document those things we believe to
be true.
Like we're going to use the same resources
we used for the last project.
We assume we can use the same contractors
as we did in the last project.
Constraints.
We also document.
A constraint is anything that impedes or
dictates the actions of the project team.
We have six.
So we'll start with the triple
constraints, or classic iron triangle,
scope, time, and cost.
They all affect each other.
But those are not the only constraints.
We also have quality, risks, uncertainties,
and resources, or lack thereof.
These are all constraints, so we need to
document any that we know about from the
get-go and continuously through our
project because they will affect us.